Mobile: +923139572272

Shah Nawaz Khan, (M.Phil. in Pharmaceutical Sciences).



Objective:

To be a part of a competitive research organization to utilize my competencies, capabilities, skills, education and experience as an innovative personnel to add to the dignity of the organization.

Permanent Address: Mohalla umar khail Gul baba District Malakand Tehsil Batkhela Khyber Pakhtun Khwa

Postal address: Amir Traders' main bazar Batkhela District Malakand Tehsil Batkhela Khyber Pakhtun Khwa

Education

Session.	Degree/Certificates	cGPA/Percentage
2012 – 2014	University of Malakand, Dir, Pakistan Master of Philosophy, Pharmaceutical Science	cGPA 3.58
2004 – 2009	Gomal University, Dera Ismail Khan, Pakistan Doctor of Pharmacy, Pharmaceutical Science	62.54 %
2002 – 2004	Oxford Education Academy F.Sc., Pre-Medical	61.09 %
2001 – 2002	Oxford Education Academy Batkhela Matriculation, Science	76 %

Thesis: "Pharmacological Activities and One Pot Two Step Synthesis of Novel Amide Derivative".

Research Experience:

2012 – 2014 M.Phil. Scholar

University of Malakand, Department of Pharmacy Dīr, Pakistan

Synthesis and Pharmacological activities of Synthetic/Natural Compounds High Pressure Liquid Chromatography, Column Chromatography, Analysis, Separation, Characterization,

Identification,

Skills & Activities:

Skills Pharmacological Activities, Material Characterization, Organic Synthesis,

Medicinal and Pharmaceutical Chemistry

Languages English, Pashto, Urdu

Scientific software ChemOffice 2012, Endnote X7.2, Graphpad V, ChemSpider,

Publication Highlights:

Journal Publications:

- 1. **S. N. Khan**, M. Shoaib, S. W. A. Shah, M. Shuaib, G. Nabi, H. Muhammad, "*Pharmacological Activities and One Pot two Step Synthesis of Novel (E)-N-(1-Methyl-4-oxoimidazolidine-2-viledene)benzamide*" WJZ., 10 (4): 241-246, 2015.
- 2. G. Nabi, H. Muhammad, S. N. Khan, A. A. Khan, "Etiological Factors of Esophageal Cancer." *AEJTS.*, 7 (3): 188-197, 2015

3. A. A. Shah, H. Muhammad, N. Farooqi, N. Gul, A. A. Khan, G. Nabi and S. N. Khan, "Association of TORCH Agents with Spontaneous Abortion in Patients with Bad Obstetric History" WJZ., 10 (4): 291-294, 2015.

Professional Experience:

Stanley Pharmaceutical Industry, (April 2009-20th October 2011)

Peshawar, KPK

1. Dispensing Pharmacist (April to June 2009):

Responsibilities:

- a. To dispense the exact raw materials according to the formulation.
- b. Exact amount of weight for drug preparation
- c. To dispense the raw material according to control environment already mentioned according to the stability of materials i-e temperature and humidity.
- d. To check the stability of raw materials which are being dispensed or stored at raw material store.

2. Quality Control Analyst (Jun 2009 to 20th October 2011):

Responsibilities:

- a. Analytical method validation,
- b. Supervision of QC Department.
- c. In-house calibration of OC Instruments and Glassware
- d. Analysis of raw material, bulk and finished product on UV-Spectrophotometer,
- e. To develop testing methods for the raw material as well as finished product,
- f. Improvement of QC documentation, Packaging materials analysis and their proofing
- g. To train the fresh QC Analyst on instruments, composition of registration files for exports and implementation of cGMP & cGLP practices.

Internship:

Institute of Child Health Lahore: October 15, 2008 to November 30, 2008

Lahore Punjab

- . Worked as interne for 6 weeks in different department of hospital i-e Central Pharmacy, Accident and Emergency Pharmacy, TPN and Aseptic Section, Extemporaneous Pharmacy and Allocated Wards
- 2. Long case study was conducted on IDDM patient. At which errors in Doctor Prescription is detected and were accepted

Professional skills:

- 1. Valuable academic and practical experience in pharmaceutical preparation, Organic synthesis design and procedures, pharmacological activities, analytical methods modification and development,
- 2. Research, thesis, paper and report writing.
- 3. Eagerness towards scientific innovation and experimentation.

Computer skills:

Ms Office, Internet browsing, designing, Hosting and Emails, Hardware and software management, Typing speed of over 150 words per minute.

Team player:

An employee who values a team environment, with the capacity to be a constructive and reliable team member.

Communication skills:

Well-developed written and verbal communication skills, combined with the ability to cooperate effectively with team members to solve problems.

References:

Professor Farid Khan Ex. Vice Chancellor Gomal University D. I. Khan Cell # +923005792890 Professor Altaf Department of Urdu University of Hazara Cell # +923129316202